Finding Aid for Media Resources Center (University of Michigan) films and videotapes, 1930s and 1948-1987
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Series FF, Film File
  - Screen News Digest, 1960, 851831-FF-211-b; Expedition to Antarctica. Includes historical film of Robert Scott's failed attempt to reach the south pole and of several of Richard Bird's expeditions, Pres. Roosevelt welcoming Bird home, and footage of "Little America" U.S. Antarctic camp.
    - Original:, 16mm film
  - Screen News Digest, 1961 1961, 851831-FF-212; A newsreel by Telenews of the Day Prod. features dedication of a memorial to Robert Hutchins Goddard at Goddard Space Flight Center, includes rare footage of Goddard's early rocketry experiments and interview with Mrs. Goddard and Werner Von Braun. Features: Robert Hutchins Goddard, Werner Von Braun
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sof, 700
  - Cicada, 851831-FF-213; Footage of cicadas emerging from ground, in trees etc. includes extreme close-ups. Filmed for TVC Series B program "Sounds of Cicadas".
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sil, 350
  - James K. Pollock circa 1957, 851831-FF-214; Film of Henry Bretton interviewing James K. Pollock on the current German election campaign. Pollock discusses the Adenauer campaign and what the election could mean for U.S. foreign policy. (Apparently filmed for a TVC program.)Features: James K. Pollock, UM-Pol. Sci.;Henry Bretton, UM-Pol. Sci.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 700, 00:14:40
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-FF214.flv
  - Nuclear Conference 1954, The following films were made at the time of a conference of scientists, educators, journalists, and government officials at the UM on the technical, political, and social consequences of the development of nuclear power.
    - Nuclear Conference 1954, 851831-FF-215-a; Duane Roller.;A physicist who is editor of Scientific Monthly discusses the impact of the atomic age on science journalism, stressing the importance of openness and intellectual honesty and problems created by the need for secrecy in atomic research. Features: Duane Roller
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sound, 192, 00:05:23
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF215-a.flv
    - Nuclear Conference, 851831-FF-215-b; Jerome Luntz.; Editor of Nucleonics Magazine discusses the impact of the atomic age on information and communication in society, the public's need to gain a basic understanding of nuclear energy, and the impact of secrecy needs in atomic research. Features: Jerome Luntz
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sound, 224, 00:06:16
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF215-b.flv
    - Nuclear Conference 1954, 851831-FF-215-c; Studio interviews and film of proceedings of the conference on nuclear energy held at the University of Michigan. (This consists of several reels of negatives, workprints, and other footage used in TVC programs on the conference.)
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos;pos, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 850;1100
  - AIM - Alumni Investment in Michigan 1956, 851831-FF-216; Alexander Ruthven discusses the University of Michigan's development council and the Alumni Fund, interviews with several student's who received financial aid from the Alumni Fund. Features: Alexander Ruthven, UM-Pres.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 800
  - Frank O'Connor, 851831-FF-217; Writer Frank O'Connor, in his office, reads from his own work - a story about his school days. Features: Frank O'Connor
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 700
  - Salk Vaccine Promotion circa 1955, 851831-FF-218-a-b; A film explaining the development, testing, and use of the Salk polio vaccine featuring Jonas Salk, Thomas Francis and other leading figures in polio research. The film was aimed at doctors. Sponsored by Eli Lilly Company and includes footage of Salk inoculating child, Closed Circuit on Dumont Network. Features: Jonas Salk ;Thomas Francis, UM-Med. ;Basil O'Connor ;Hart E. Van Ryper (Note: the film was spliced out of order, the streaming file has been edited to correct the order.) (Copyright to the film is held by the Eli Lllly Company.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sof, 1917, 00:53:24
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-FF218-a-b.flv
  - Salk Vaccine Promotion circa 1955, 851831-FF-218-c; Appears to be kinescope negative of 218-b. Includes footage of Salk inoculating child Features: Jonas Salk ;Thomas Francis, UM-Med. ;Basil O'Connor ;Hart E. Van Ryper
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 753, 00:20:57
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 5)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-FF218-c.flv
  - Beaumont Memorial 1954, Several reels of film from the Series H program "Beaumont Memorial" on the dedication of the Mackinac Island memorial to pioneer physician William Beaumont, including a nearly complete version of the program, also, footage of the ceremony, Features: Emil Lorch, UM-Arch.(See also Archives film number 458 for additional footage of the dedication ceremony.
    - Beaumont Memorial 1954, 851831-FF-219-1; Several reels of film from the Series H program "Beaumont Memorial" on the dedication of the Mackinac Island memorial to pioneer physician William Beaumont, including a nearly complete version of the program, also, footage of the ceremony, Features: Emil Lorch, UM-Arch.
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg;wp, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 600;600
    - Beaumont Memorial, 851831-FF-219-2; an interview with Emil Lorch consultant on the historic site restoration, interview with Dr. Frederick Coller about the significance of Beaumont's work and the development of the memorial, and footage of the memorial and restored building and museum.
      - Original:, 16mm film
    - Beaumont Memorial, 851831-FF-219-3
      - Original:, 16mm film
  - Thai Ambassador Visits Phoenix Lab 1955, 851831-FF-220-a; Footage of Thailand's ambassador to the U.S. on a tour of the UM Phoenix Memorial Laboratory, includes his arrival on North Campus, shots of the laboratory and several engineering professors, and footage of North Campus construction sites.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 200
  - Thai Ambassador Visits Phoenix Lab 1955, 851831-FF-220-b; Thai ambassador and UM engineering professors discuss the UM Phoenix Memorial Project for study of the peaceful uses of atomic energy, Thailand's interest in nuclear power, and possible training of Thai engineers at UM.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 400
  - Ford Reactor Dedication 1956
    - Ford Reactor Dedication 1956, 851831-FF-222-a; Film footage of the dedication ceremonies for the Ford Nuclear Reactor at the University of Michigan, includes footge of comments by Harlan Hatcher, Ralph Sawyer, and several engineering professors. Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres. ;Ralph Sawyer, UM-VP
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos;b/w, sil;sof, 813, 813
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 813, 00:22:32
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF222-a.flv
    - Ford Reactor Dedication 1956, 851831-FF-222-b; Continues coverage of the dedication ceremonies for the Ford Nuclear Reactor.
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos;neg; b/w;b/w;b/w, sof;sil; 730;730;730
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 730, 00:20:16
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF222-b.flv
    - Ford Reactor Dedication 1956, 851831-FF-222-c; Footage of the Ford Nuclear Reactor at the University of Michigan, at the time of its dedication, includes shots of the reactor pool, rods, and instrument panels.
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos; b/w;b/w, sil, 664
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 664, 00:18:32
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF222-c.flv
    - Ford Reactor Dedication 1956, 851831-FF-222-d; Continues coverage of the dedication ceremonies for the Ford Nuclear Reactor.
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg;neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sof, 901, 901
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sof, 901, 00:20:22
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF222-d.flv
    - Ford Reactor Dedication 1956, 851831-FF-222-e; Continues coverage of the dedication ceremonies for the Ford Nuclear Reactor.
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg;neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sof, 811, 811
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sof, 811, 00:22:34
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF222-e.flv
    - Ford Reactor Dedication 1956, 851831-FF-222-f; Continues coverage of the dedication ceremonies for the Ford Nuclear Reactor. Actual footage of the reactor and its lab.
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg;neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sof, 101, 101
      - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sof, 101, 00:02:51
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF222-f.flv
  - Flint College 1955, Footage of Flint Community College campus, and ceremony marking its becoming the University of Michigan Flint Campus, and construction of UM-Flint.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 901
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 00:25:02
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-FF223-a.flv
  - Flint College 1955, 851831-FF-223-b; Continues footage of University of Michigan Flint dedication ceremony, Harlan Hatcher delivering address. Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 575
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof
  - Flint College 1955, 851831-FF-223-c; Brief footage of UM-Flint dedication ceremony and of Harlan Hatcher and college officials in the lobby. Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg;pos, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 20;16
  - Ann Arbor Parade 1955, 851831-FF-224; Footage of a parade down State Street in Ann Arbor, Michigan.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 100
  - Registration 1955 1955, 851831-FF-225; Footage of University of Michigan class registration in Waterman Gymnasium.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 100
  - Lantern Night 1955, 851831-FF-226; Several women's choral groups perform at the annual "Lantern Night" sponsored by the Women's Athletic Association.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg;neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 125;90
  - Band Day 1955 1955, 851831-FF-227; Footage of marching bands performing at Michigan Stadium on high school band day.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 120
  - UM Marching Band 1955, 851831-FF-228; Footage of a half-time show by the UM Marching Band at Michigan Stadium. Features: Marching Band
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil
  - Michifish 1955, 851831-FF-229; Footage of a performance by Michifish, the UM synchronized swimming team.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 200
  - U Nu Visits Phoenix Lab 1955, 851831-FF-230-a; Film of tour of Phoenix Memorial Laboratory by U Nu of Burma, includes a discussion of the Phoenix Project for research in peaceful use of atomic energy, use of radiation in medicine, and the possibility of sending Burmese students to UM. Features: U Nu
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 400
  - U Nu Visits Phoenix Lab 1955, 851831-FF-230-b; Continues coverage of U Nu's tour of the Phoenix Lab and of a reception for him at the Clements Library. Features: U Nu
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 200
  - Rae and Brandon 1955, 851831-FF-231; Footage of an interview in which James Rae refutes allegations that UM athletes, football player Ron Kramer in particular, had received improper financial aid through a loophole in Big 10 regulations. Features: James Rae, UM-Med. ;Arthur Brandon, UM-Jour.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 145
  - Graduation 1955 1955, 851831-FF-232; Footage of graduation ceremony in Michigan Stadium, includes shots of the procession and awarding of diplomas.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg;neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 250;90
  - Phoenix Laboratory Dedication, 851831-FF-233; Brief footage of the installation of the donor plaque in the lobby of the Phoenix Memorial Laboratory and a demonstration of equipment for remote handling of radioactive material.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 80
  - High School Band Day 1954 1954, 851831-FF-234; Film footage of performance by massed bands at Michigan Stadium on annual high school band day.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 200
  - Japanese Ambassador Visits Japanese Center 1955, 851831-FF-235; Japanese ambassador to the United States visits the library of the Center for Japanese Studies at the University of Michigan, discusses the work of the Center.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sof, 155
  - TVC Film circa 1955, 851831-FF-236; Film of the facilities, equipment, and staff of the University of Michigan Television Center shows staff and technicians at work during production of a television program.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 200
  - Navy ROTC circa 1952, 851831-FF-237; Footage of UM Naval ROTC members working in classrooms and training on anti-aircraft guns and other equipment, also short footage of the Air Force ROTC band.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 170
  - Ann Arbor Pioneer High School 1956, 851831-FF-238; Footage at what was apparently an open house at Pioneer High School, includes shot of the exterior and of classrooms and laboratories and an assembly in the gymnasium.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 150
  - Diag Scenes circa 1953, 851831-FF-239; Footage of students on the Diag and steps of General Library.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos;neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 150;150
  - Old Outpatient Clinic circa 1953, 851831-FF-240; Footage of facilities and staff at the old Out-Patient Clinic of the University of Michigan Hospital, includes shots of doctors examining patients, the registration desk, and laboratories.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 500
  - Boy Scout Meeting circa 1956, 851831-FF-241-a; Footage from the Boy Scout Leader National Training Meeting held on the UM campus, includes interviews with the chief scout administrator and Harold Stassen. Features: Harold Stassen
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos;neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 500;500
  - Boy Scout Meeting circa 1956, 851831-FF-241-b; Footage of the Boy Scout Leader National Training meeting held on UM campus, includes shots of a meeting in Rackham Auditorium, displays on the Diag, and an encampment on Ferry Field.
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 180
  - Zoology Film 1955, 851831-FF-242; Footage of professors and students working in the zoology laboratory. (5 reels of negatives, ca. 1200 feet.)
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1200
  - Literature School circa 1955, 851831-FF-243-a; Film footage of classroom scenes, class registration in Haven Hall, and a convocation in Rackham Auditorium. Apparently filmed for recruiting film for the College of Literature, Sciences, and the Arts.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sil, 183
  - Literature School circa 1955, 851831-FF-243-b; Footage of classrooms and laboratories, a group of faculty members in a meeting, several interviews of freshman students as part of the Principal - Freshman Conferences in which high school principals interview freshmen.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos;neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 600;400
  - Salk Vaccine Announcement 1955, 851831-FF-244; Footage of the press conference announcing the results of the Salk polio vaccine tests. Salk describes the field tests and analyzes the results. Jonas Salk, Tommy Francis and Basil O'Connor answer questions. (Not complete coverage.)Features: Jonas Salk ;Thomas Francis, UM-SPH; Basil O'Connor
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sof, 739, 00:20:31
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-FF244.flv
  - Salk Vaccine Announcement 1955, 851831-FF-244-a; Footage from the press conference announcing the results of the Salk polio vaccine tests. Mostly shots of press gallery and crowd, shots of passing out report some of Salk and others at podium and informal, exteriors of Rackham. Features: Jonas Salk ;Thomas Francis, UM-SPH; BASIL O'Connor
    - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 817, 00:22:46
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-FF244-a.flv
  - Salk Vaccine Test Procedure 1955, 851831-FF-245; Incomplete footage of a press conference by Thomas Francis, director of the Salk polio vaccine field tests, discusses methodology but not results of the tests. This was held a week prior to announcement of the test results. Features: Thomas Francis, UM-Med.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos, b/w, sil, 1028, 00:28:31
    - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
    - Streaming File:, 851831-FF245.flv
  - Slausson Junior High Operetta, 851831-FF-246; Footage of Slausson Jr. High School's production of the original operetta "The Bell and the Bellhop." Also interviews with principal Harold Logan and music teacher Merton Kellog about producing the musical.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos;neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sil, 1000;1000
  - Women's Maternity Hospital, 851831-FF-247; Miscellaneous footage of the UM Women's Hospital maternity section, includes shots of patient rooms, examination rooms, laboratories, delivery room, and kitchen facilities, also footage of doctors and nurses attending patients.
    - Original:, 16mm film, pos;pos;pos;pos, b/w;b/w;b/w;b/w, sil;sil;sil;sil, 350;300;250;100
  - Psychology Experiments circa 1956, 851831-FF-248
    - Psychology Experiments circa 1956, 851831-FF-248; Film footage of several psychological and physiological experiments on monkeys, rats, and rabbits conducted by University of Michigan researchers. Include shots of laboratories and scientific equipment and researchers at work.
      - Original:, 16mm film
    - Psychology Experiment circa 1956, 851831-FF-248-a; Devalois.; Footage of experiment conducted by UM researcher Russell Devalois. Features: Russell Devalois
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments circa 1956, 851831-FF-248-b; Domino.; Footage of an experiment conducted by Edward Domino of the UM Medical School Department of Pharmacology. Features: Edward Domino, UM-Med.
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments circa 1956, 851831-FF-248-c; Coombs.; Footage of an experiment conducted by UM psychology professor Clyde Coombs. Features: Clyde H. Coombs, UM-Psych.
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments circa 1956, 851831-FF-248-d; McCleary, Meyers.; Footage of experiment conducted by UM professors Robert McCleary and Muriel Meyers. Features: Robert McCleary, UM-Psych ;Muriel Meyers, UM-Med.
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments circa 1956, 851831-FF-248-e; Olds.; Footage of experiment conducted by UM psychology professor James Olds. Features: James Olds, UM-Psych.
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments circa 1956, 851831-FF-248-f; Walker.; Footage of experiment conducted by UM psychology professor Edward Walker. Features: Edward Walker, UM-Psych.
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
    - Psychology Experiments circa 1956, 851831-FF-248-g; Footage of experiments on brain cells conducted by UM psychology professors.
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 800
  - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-1; Twelve reels of film negatives, consists of documentary footage of "Operation Deep Freeze," a scientific expediting to Antarctica. Shot by UM Television Center Staff. Includes footage of camp at "Little America", experiments, and scenery, sea voyage, and Antarctic scenes.
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-1
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 981, 00:27:17
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-1.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-2
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 959, 00:26:41
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-2.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-3
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1037, 00:28:50
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-3.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-4
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 878, 00:24:33
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-4.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-5
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1038, 00:28:52
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-5.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-6
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1055, 00:29:20
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-6.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-7
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1099, 0030:32
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-7.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-8
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 986, 00:27:26
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-8.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-9
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1076, 0029:55
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-9.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-10
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1079, 00:30:00
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-10.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-11
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1120, 00:31:07
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
      - Streaming File:, 851831-FF249-11.flv
    - Operation Deep Freeze, 851831-FF-249-12
      - Original:, 16mm film, neg, b/w, sil, 1234, 00:34:11
      - Use copy:, DVD (Box 6)
  - Ford Donation, 851831-FF-250; Two reels of magnetic sound track of press conference and ceremony announcing gift of Fairlane Mansion from Ford Motor Company to the University of Michigan for establishment of the UM Dearborn Campus. Features: Harlan Hatcher, UM-Pres.
    - Original:, 16mm film, sot;sot, 900;900
  - Arms Control Conference, Films #283 - 297 consist of interview footage with participants in the first international symposium on arms control sponsored by the University of Michigan. Participants included government officials, representatives of defense contractors, academic specialists in disarmament research, and peace activists. Some of this footage was incorporated into the Series B programs "Report on Arms Control." Most of the films include negatives, workprints and magnetic sound tracks.
    - Arms Control: McNaughton, 851831-FF-283-a; McNaughton.; Defense Department official discusses Pentagon weapons planning and arms control. Features: John T. McNaughton
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 540;540
    - Arms Control: McNaughton, 851831-FF-283-b; McNaughton.
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 206;206
    - Arms Control: Hudson, 851831-FF-284-a; Publisher of "World Peace Report" discusses efforts to promote and disseminate scholarly research in the field of peace studies.
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil;sot, 410;410;410
    - Arms Control: Hudson, 851831-FF-284-b; Hudson.
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof, 195;195
    - Arms Control: Aaron, 851831-FF-285; Aaron. Director of Arms Control at the Pentagon discusses the arms negotiation process.
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof;sot, 265;500;500
    - Arms Control: Karpov, 851831-FF-286-a; Karpov.
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp, b/w, sil;sot, 575;400
    - Arms Control: Karpov, 851831-FF-286-b; Karpov.
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sil;sil, 200;200
    - Arms Control: Taylor, 851831-FF-287-a; Taylor.; Chairman of the National Research Council on Peace Studies talks about the council's activities and the role of peace organizations in the peace and disarmament movement.
      - Original:, 16mm film, wp; neg, b/w;b/w, sof;sof;sot, 500;500